it's easy to forget when you're
当你在这样的地方时很容易忘记，
somewhere like this but the world has
但世界
suffered from a series of global
遭受了一系列全球性
catastrophes disasters that have wiped
灾难灾难，这些灾难已经消灭
out 99% of all the species that have
了所有曾经生活过的物种的 99%，
but the forces that wiped out many of
但消灭
our ancestors are still at work today
我们许多祖先的力量仍然存在 今天的工作
all we have to protect us is a wisp of
我们所需要保护的只是一缕
atmosphere and all we have to stand on
大气，我们所
is a thin crust mankind could be the
要做的只是一层薄薄的地壳人类可能成为
next dominant species to face extinction
下一个面临灭绝的主要物种
this is the story of how vulnerable we
这是一个关于我们真的是多么脆弱的故事
our planet has been shaped by an endless
我们的星球已经被塑造了
cycle of destruction and renewal the
毁灭和更新的无休止循环的
result 99% of all the species that have
结果 99%
ever lived and now extinct but we tend
曾经生活过的物种现在已经灭绝，但我们
to forget that the very forces that
往往忘记，
created all this havoc are just as
造成所有这些破坏的
powerful as ever we've been lucky so far
力量与以往一样强大，到目前为止我们很幸运
we humans haven't been confronted by a
人类尚未面临
truly global crisis yet but history
真正的全球危机，但历史
reveals that we're much more at risk
表明，我们面临的风险
than we might think another big one
比我们想象的
could be just around the corner to
要大得多，以
understand the sheer scale of Earth's 4
了解地球 4
and 1/2 billion year history imagine it
和 1/2 b 的庞大规模 亿万年的历史把它想象
as the 24 hours on a clock earth formed
成一个时钟地球上的 24 小时
at midnight just nine minutes later
在午夜形成，仅仅 9 分钟后
disaster struck our planet collided with
灾难袭击了我们的星球，与另一个星球相撞，
but earth survived and life evolved
但地球幸存下来，生命
then at 8:30 p.m. another disaster the
在晚上 8 点 30 分进化。 晚上 10 点 40 分，另一场灾难
entire planet froze over
整个星球都冻结了
10:40 p.m. massive volcanic eruptions
。 大规模的火山喷发
poisoned the planet
毒害了地球
life was nearly wiped out
生命，几乎
and at 11:38 p.m. a giant asteroid
在晚上 11 点 38 分毁灭。 一颗巨大的小行星
killed off the dinosaurs leading to the
杀死了恐龙，导致
rise of the mammals it was only in the
了哺乳动物的兴起 只有在
closing minutes of the day that our
一天的最后几分钟，我们的
planet became a place we'd recognize
星球才最终成为我们认识的地方，在距
finally and under a minute to midnight a
午夜不到一分钟的时间里，一个
tough new species marched towards world
艰难的新物种向着世界的
domination they spread rapidly adapting
统治进军 迅速传播
to every challenge this new species was
适应每一个挑战 这个新物种是
85,000 years ago we were just heading
85,000 年前的智人 我们今天刚刚
out of Africa today we're everywhere
离开非洲 我们无处不在
this is the story of what happened since
这是自
humans walk the planet and it shows just
人类在地球上行走以来发生的故事，它表明
how vulnerable we really are again and
我们再次变得多么脆弱
again our ancestors confronted
我们的祖先再次面临
catastrophes all of them were different
灾难 他们所有人都不同 但他们中的
but any one of them could have stopped
任何一个都可以阻止
human civilization in its tracks
人类文明的发展
the first disaster struck India 74
7.4 万年前的今天第一次灾难袭击了印度
this event can be found in the most
可以
unlikely place inside the cells of our
在细胞内最不可能的地方找到这一事件的证据 我们的
bodies the story of the human race is
身体 人类的故事
written in our genes our genes control
写在我们的基因中 我们的基因
not only what we look like they also
不仅控制着我们的外貌 它们还
record evidence of past disasters for
记录了过去 对于
geneticists Steve and Oppenheimer
遗传学家史蒂夫和奥本海默
it's a crucial clue
来说，这是一条重要的线索，
as you move away from Africa the overall
当你离开非洲时
genetic diversity reduces in different
，不同种群的整体遗传多样性会减少，
populations until you get to the Native
直到你到达美洲
American populations which have the
原住民种群，它们
least diversity of of all but there is
的多样性是所有种群中多样性最低的，但有
one place where there's an anomaly
一个地方存在
that's India
异常 印度
in India genetic diversity is much much
在印度的遗传多样性远
lower than it should be
低于应有的水平
Oppenheimer believes some kind of
奥本海默认为一定是某种
disaster must have struck India's early
灾难袭击了印度的早期
settlers something so severe that their
定居者 事情如此严重以至于他们的
descendants genetic diversity is still
后代遗传多样性今天仍然
affected today whatever it was this
受到影响，无论是什么这场
ancient disaster came close to wiping
古老的灾难几乎
out the whole subcontinent it's
消灭了整个 次大陆
difficult to estimate the size a
很难估计减少的规模，
reduction but it might have been down to
但
about 600 people in the whole of India
整个印度的人口可能减少到大约 600 人，
whatever struck India it was absolutely
无论袭击印度，这绝对是
devastating something powerful enough to
毁灭性的，足以
wipe out most of the population there is
消灭大部分人口，当然这是
of course a very obvious catastrophe
一场非常明显的
which is clearly dated in the right time
灾难 显然日期在正确的时
zone and that is Toba toba is an
区，即 Toba toba 是
Indonesian supervolcano its last
印度尼西亚的超级火山 它的最后一次
eruption is described by volcanologists
喷发被火山学家描述
as mega-colossal that's as big as it
为与 74000 年前的日期一样大
Earth's history it's less than two
地球历史的时钟 距
seconds to midnight 74 thousand years
7.4 万
ago the Indonesian supervolcano Toba
年前的午夜不到两秒 印度尼西亚的多巴火山
erupted our ancient ancestors were faced
爆发 我们的远古祖先面临
with a terrifying threat
着可怕的威胁
volcanoes are one of the most powerful
火山是地球上最强大的力量之一，
forces on the planet they can devastate
它们可以摧毁
whole regions and even affect global
整个地区，甚至影响全球
climate
气候
this is Mount Augustine off the coast of
这是阿拉斯加海岸附近的奥古斯丁山
Alaska it's not a super volcano but it
它不是一座超级火山，但它
does illustrate the raw power of even a
确实说明了即使是 2006 年
fairly small eruption it last blew in
上次喷发的一次相当小的喷发的原始力量
volcanologists John Power is monitoring
火山学家约翰·鲍尔正在监测
how it's changed since then one of the
自那时以来它是如何变化的 这座火山是美国
most active volcanoes in the Cook Inlet
最活跃的火山之一 库克湾
during the last eruption here Augustine
地区上次喷发时奥古斯丁在这里
blasted out 65 million cubic meters of
喷出 6500 万立方米的
rock so much debris that the summit grew
岩石 太多碎片 山顶增长
by around 70 meters
了大约 70 米
the eruption here was big though it was
这里的喷发很大，虽然它
nothing compared to the power that could
与
be unleashed by a supervolcano
超级火山释放的能量相比微不足道，
but studying smaller eruptions like
但研究像奥古斯丁这样的小喷发
Augustine give scientists an insight
让科学家们深入了解
into the incredible power of the Toba
多巴喷发的惊人力量
eruption 74,000 years ago
74,000 几年前，
we're sitting on Augustin Island which
我们坐在奥古斯丁岛上，这里
is the home of Augustine volcano which
是奥古斯丁火山的所在地，
you see behind us we are at the very
你在我们身后看到我们
northern end of what's called the Ring
位于所谓的
of Fire the Ring of Fire is the chain of
火环的最北端火环
volcanoes that surrounds the Pacific
是环绕
Ocean it's the world's most volcanically
太平洋的火山链 世界上火山
active region Mount Toba lies in
活动最活跃的地区 多巴山位于
Indonesia at its western edge here and
印度尼西亚的西部边缘，这里有
many of these volcanoes in the Ring of
许多火山位于火环中，火山
Fire you have very explosive types of
爆发类型非常具有
elevation in the atmosphere there's no
爆炸性 没有任何
place where things are as quite as
地方
have produced some of the most violent
像印度尼西亚一样活跃
the Taliban eruption was the biggest on
Anet 塔利班火山爆发是
earth for two million years the forces
地球上两百万年来最大的火山爆发
are quite extreme during one of these
在这些大型爆炸性火山爆发之一中，力量非常极端
magma that's coming up underneath the
岩浆从
volcano inside that magma you have a lot
火山下方涌出 岩浆内部 你有
of gas and so on that's absorbed inside
很多气体 等等 被吸收在
the magma itself and it's really this
内部 岩浆本身 正是这种
gas pressure that is driving a lot of
气压推动了
the eruption
很多喷发
an average volcano might contain enough
一座普通的火山可能含有足够的
gas and magma for the eruption to last
气体和岩浆，足以让喷发
for hours towba must have erupted for
持续数小时 towba 一定已经喷发了
days
数天，
but while such eruptions are rare
但虽然这种喷发很少见，但
disturbingly the volcanoes that cause
令人不安的是导致它们的火山
them aren't 47 supervolcano sites have
世界上不是已经发现了 47 个超级火山遗址
been discovered worldwide many are no
许多已经
longer active but a few are and they
不再活跃，但有一些已经
pose a real threat to human society the
对人类社会构成了真正的威胁
most famous one of all lies in the
其中最著名的一个位于
United States
美国
Yellowstone this bizarre landscape
黄石公园 这个奇异的景观
attracts over 3 million visitors every
每年吸引超过 300 万游客
year they come here to witness the raw
他们来这里是为了见证
power of the parks famous geezers
公园著名的 geezers 的原始力量
Yellowstone has the largest collection
黄石公园拥有最多
of such hydrothermal features anywhere
的此类水热 l 地球上任何地方的特征
on earth two-thirds of the world's
世界上三分之二的
geezers are in this one park that takes
geezers 都在这个
a lot of heat in fact it takes a super
需要大量热量的公园里 事实上它需要
volcano like Toba only hidden below
像多巴这样的超级火山 只隐藏在
ground the last super-eruption here was
地下 最后一次超级火山喷发是在
640 thousand years ago long before
64 万年前，早于
humans ruled the planet but even after
人类 统治了这个星球，但即使过
all this time you can still see evidence
了这么久，你仍然可以看到
of this ancient blast and the volcano
这次古老爆炸的证据，火山
itself remains active one day it will
本身仍然活跃，有一天它会
erupt again pragya physicists like bob
再次喷发 像鲍勃·史密斯这样的物理学家
smith yellowstone is a vital Research
黄石是一个重要的研究
Center
中心
for decades Smith has been studying the
史密斯几十年来一直在研究
Yellowstone Caldera the giant volcanic
黄石火山口
crater in the center of the park his
公园中心的巨大火山口，他的
work reveals just how devastating the
作品揭示
eruption of Toba would have been
了多巴火山喷发
pretending here on the east side of
在黄石湖东侧的破坏性
front of us is actually the caldera
，我们面前的陡峭山丘实际上是火山口
boundary and the caldera essentially
边界，火山口基本上
occupies this entire expanse of the
占据了 整个广阔的
landscape that we can see this whole
景观 我们可以看到整个
system exploded out during the last
系统在上一次
giant eruption this is a giant caldera
巨大的喷发中爆炸了 这是一个巨大的火山
probably one of the biggest in the world
口 是世界上已知最大的火山之一，
that's known and this is active the
并且处于活跃状态
sheer size of the Yellowstone system
黄石系统的庞大规模
makes it a key location for the study of
使其成为
the ancient tober super eruption the
研究古代托伯超级喷发的关键地点
60 kilometer by 40 kilometers dopa has a
40 公里外，多巴有一个
large lake occupying the caldera as you
大湖占据火山口，正如您
know also in lake so it's very similar
所知，湖中的火山口
in size
大小非常相似，
these hills and rocks were sculpted by
这些山丘和岩石由
immense forces the home landscape has
巨大的力量雕刻而成 家庭景观
been shaped by the giant volcanic
由
furnace below the magma chamber this is
岩浆房下方的巨大火山熔炉塑造，这
the zone where molten rock gathers under
是 熔岩
immense pressure deep below the caldera
在火山口深处的巨大压力下聚集的区域
the bigger the magma chamber the
岩浆房
deadlier the eruption
越大 喷发越致命
Smith's work here at Yellowstone shows
史密斯在黄石公园的工作表明
Tobi's magma chamber would have been
托比的岩浆房会
huge this is his laboratory
很大 这是他的实验室
we're here at a site on the east side of
我们在东边的一个地点
the caldera where we have a seismograph
我们有一个地震仪的火山口，
which records ground motions of relate
它记录
to the vibrations of the earth when they
与地球振动有关的地面运动，当它们
have the passage of seismic waves so we
有地震 w 时 aves 所以
a year here by mapping his seismic data
我们通过绘制他的地震数据来记录每年 2 到 3000 次地震
Bob can estimate the size of the magma
Bob 可以估计岩浆房的大小
chamber his results are stunning
他的结果令人震惊
this simulation shows the whole United
这个模拟显示整个
States Yellowstone Park lies near the
美国黄石公园位于中间附近，
middle its boundary marked in green
用绿色
Yellowstone Lake is marked in blue the
黄石湖标记 以蓝色标记 红色标记
edge of the volcanic caldera in red
火山口边缘
Bob seismic data plotted below the
绘制在地表下方的 Bob 地震数据
surface shows the enormous size of the
显示
magma system beneath the caldera
火山口下方的岩浆系统巨大
size of the city of London
伦敦市的大小
that's an awful lot of magma scientists
很多岩浆科学家
now believe that topaz magma chamber was
现在认为黄玉岩浆房
roughly the same size and the scary
的大小大致相同，可怕
thing is that if that amount of magma
的是，如果这种数量的岩浆
erupted again it would be absolutely
再次喷发，那将绝对是
devastating and the aftermath would
毁灭性的，后果将
affect us all but the problem wouldn't
影响我们所有人 问题
be the red-hot magma the real killer
不在于炽热的岩浆，真正的
would be volcanic ash when the magma
杀手是火山灰，当岩浆
actually finally makes it to the surface
最终到达
the gas pressure will drive that magnet
地表气压将驱动磁铁
fractured pulverize of intuitive
破碎
volcanologist would call ash this is
火山学家将火山学家称为灰烬 这是
pulverized rock and minerals all ground
粉状的岩石和矿物质
up together by the explosive forces that
被爆炸力粉碎在一起
reach the very edge of space this
太空边缘
footage from the Space Shuttle of the
来自
Russian volcano Mount Khrushchev sky
俄罗斯赫鲁晓夫火山
erupting shows how high ash can be
喷发的航天飞机的这段镜头显示了在七万四千年前，可以将多高的火山灰
blasted into the atmosphere
喷入大气层
this was just the beginning as all those
这只是开始，因为所有这些
gases and and pulverized rock rise up
气体和粉状岩石都在上升
it's hot very hot about eleven hundred
它很热 非常热 大约
degrees centigrate when it comes out
1100 摄氏度 当它出来时
it'll rise up first buoyantly under its
它会首先在它自己的热量下有浮力上升
own heat and as it begins to cool it
，当它开始冷却时它
will become too heavy for the atmosphere
会变得太重，大气
to support it will rush back down the
无法支撑它会冲回
sides of the volcano this creates a very
火山的两侧 这产生了一种非常
hazardous phenomenon that we refer to as
危险的现象，我们
a pyroclastic flow these superheated ash
称之为火山碎屑流 这些过热的灰
flows can be immense at Ober they buried
流在 Obe 可能是巨大的 r 他们将这片土地埋
the landscape up to 200 metres deep any
得深达 200 米
humans nearby would have been
附近的任何人类都会被
annihilated but even those outside this
消灭，但即使是在这个
initial danger zone weren't safe
最初的危险区域之外的人也不安全
Tobi's volcanic ash traveled for
Tobi 的火山灰移动了
thousands of miles
数千
there was a massive release of ash and
英里 火山灰大量释放
that ash went Northwest in the Indian
火山灰向西北移动
Ocean and covered India 12 and a half
印度洋并覆盖了印度 12.5
million square miles of the Earth's
万平方英里的地球
surface were covered in ash anyone
表面被火山灰覆盖 任何
living in the Fallout faced starvation
生活在辐射中的人都面临
the Tober ash fall would have affected
饥饿 托贝尔火山灰的坠落将对
the vegetation in a big way in India and
印度的植被产生重大
the immediate effect of that would be
影响，其直接影响将 是
that the game that humans relied on
因为人类所依赖的游戏
didn't have any vegetation to eat and
没有任何植物可以吃
then of course the human predators being
，当然
at the top of the chain suffer much more
，处于链条顶端的人类掠食者遭受的痛苦要
the ash was deadly but volcanoes haven't
多得多，火山灰是致命的，但火山甚至不是
even deadly a weapon in their arsenal
他们武器库中的致命
the gas sulfur dioxide
武器 气体二氧化硫
towba may have released as much as 3
towba 可能释放了多达
billion tons of it volcanologist bill
30 亿吨它 火山学家 Bill
mcguire has studied how sulphur dioxide
mcguire 研究了当二氧化硫时二氧化硫
can affect the entire planet
如何影响整个地球
when sulfur dioxide gets into the
进入
atmosphere which it does with a big
大气层 伴随着一次大的
volcanic eruption it combines with water
火山喷发 它与水蒸气结合
vapor and it forms a fine mist of
并形成硫酸的细雾 大气
sulfuric acid billions of these tiny
中数十亿的这些微小的硫酸
act like tiny mirrors so they reflect
液滴就像小镜子一样，因此它们将
solar radiation back into space the
太阳辐射反射回太空
result the planet cools down and enters
结果地球冷却并
a volcanic winter
进入火山冬天
there's some debate about how much of a
有一些关于多
temperature for Toba actually led to but
巴实际导致的温度有多大的争论，但
in the extreme case it would have
在极端情况下，它会在几年内
reduced global temperatures by five to
将全球温度降低 5 到
six degrees centigrade for a period of
6 摄氏度
several years and that would have
，这将 实际上已经
literally caused most of the worlds of
导致大部分植被世界因
another super eruption today hardly bear
今天另一次超级喷发
of people if we saw a super eruption
的影响而死亡 如果我们今天看到一次超级喷发
today that resulted in that same
导致同样的
temperature drop then we would
温度下降那么我们将
experience global harvest fail you know
经历全球 收获失败，你知道
I can't see any way that that can that
我看不出有什么办法，这
can not result in billions of deaths
不会导致数十亿人死亡，
if another of Earth's active super
如果另一个 地球上活跃的超级
volcanoes does what Tober did 74
火山就像托伯 74000 年前所做的那样，
thousand years ago it would be a
这
disaster for us all
对我们所有人来说都是一场灾难
well super-eruptions on average seem to
超级火山平均
occur about every 50,000 years or so but
每 50,000 年左右就会发生一次，
of course yes
但当然是的
doesn't operate to a timetable so when
并没有按时间表运行，所以
the next one's going to occur we really
当下一次 我们
haven't a clue
真的不
the Toba supervolcano affected vast
知道多巴超级火山影响
numbers of people in India but 70,000
了印度的大量人口 但在 70,000
years ago the survivors faced a new
年前，幸存者这次面临新的
threat this time one that would affect
威胁，这将
the whole planet a global big freeze
影响整个地球 全球大冰冻
half a second to midnight on our clock
半秒到午夜 我们
of world history 21,000 years ago the
的世界历史时钟 21,000 年前，
planet was in the middle of an ice age
地球处于冰河时代的中间
throughout history ice sheets have
纵观历史，冰盖
helped form the story of the earth the
帮助形成了地球的故事
biggest one was six hundred and fifty
最大的一次发生在 6.5
million years ago when the planet was
亿年前，当时地球
virtually engulfed in ice and we had a
几乎被冰层吞没
when volcanoes broke through it and
当火山爆发并
warmed the planet again in the millions
在数百万年内再次温暖地球时，我们幸运地逃脱了
of years since that big one my sheets
，因为我的
have frequently returned just as they
床单经常返回，就像
will again one day in the future 21,000
有一天我会再次返回一样 在 21,000 年前的未来，
years ago Earth was gripped by the most
地球被
recent of these big freezes
最近的这些大冰冻所笼罩，
northern hemisphere for our ancestors
为了我们的祖先
there was no escape
，
glaciations occur on a regular cycle
冰川在北半球稳步前进 没有
caused by variations in Earth's movement
因地球在太空中运动的变化而导致的定期循环发生逃逸冰川，
through space sometimes earth moves
有时地球会
further from the Sun so the planet cools
远离 太阳，所以地球冷却
and the ice caps expand
，冰盖膨胀
the glaciers of the last ice age reached
上一个冰河时代的冰川在
their farthest point south 21,000 years
21,000 年前达到了最南端
ago a period known as the last glacial
一个被称为最后一次
maximum the last glacial maximum in in
冰期最大值的时期 欧洲的最后一次冰期最大值
Europe is about as bad as it can get and
几乎与它所能达到的一样糟糕，
that meant an ice cap three miles thick
这意味着一个 3 英里厚的冰盖
which covered half of Britain and around
覆盖了英国的一半，而
that ice cap to the south was a polar
南面的冰盖周围是一片极地
desert which didn't have ice on it but
沙漠，上面没有冰，但
also didn't have much vegetation or
也没有太多植被或
people
人类
for our ancestors it was migrated or
供我们的祖先迁徙或
they didn't return until the big Thor
直到
began around 7,000 years later
大约 7,000 年后大雷神开始
and when the glaciers retreated it
时，他们才返回，当冰川退缩时，它
changed everything
改变
released from the grip of the ice
了从冰文明的控制中释放出来的一切
civilization was finally free to begin
国家终于可以自由地开始
agriculture cities the Industrial
农业城市工业
Revolution banks you get the picture the
革命银行你明白
end of the Ice Age made it all possible
冰河时代的结束使这一切成为可能
but the irony is our civilization is now
但具有讽刺意味的是我们的文明现在
so complex that we'd be helpless if the
如此复杂以至于如果
glaciers advanced again and if there's
冰川再次前进我们将无能为力如果有
one thing that's certain it's the one
有一件事是肯定的，
day the ice will return even now
即使现在
Earth's orbit is taking it further from
地球的轨道将它
the Sun another glacial advance is due
带离太阳更远的那一天，冰会返回到另一次冰川前进的
any time
任何时候
the return of the ice would be a brutal
，只要冰的返回在 1998 年将是一次残酷的
shock in 1998 we got a glimpse of just
冲击，我们就可以瞥见它是
how brutal
多么的残酷
a nice storm hit the city of Montreal
一场大风暴袭击了蒙特利尔市
freak weather conditions created a
怪异的天气条件造成了
relentless buildup of ice 1,000
无情的冰层堆积 1,000 座
electricity pylons collapsed under its
电塔在其
weight
重量
the power supply failed millions of
下倒塌 电力供应中断 数百万
inhabitants were left without heating
居民无法取暖
and the temperature continued to fall
，气温持续
the Montreal ice storm exposed our
下降 蒙特利尔冰暴暴露了我们
society's Achilles heel our reliance on
社会的致命弱点
near-perfect conditions if the glaciers
如果冰川再次前进，我们对近乎完美的条件的
much we could do to protect ourselves
依赖 我们无能为力来保护自己
inevitably a new Ice Age if it occurred
不可避免地，如果新的冰河时代发生
very rapidly would lead to complete
得非常迅速，将导致完全的
social and economic breakdown people
社会和经济崩溃，人们
would move towards equator from the
将从
northern country like the United States
像美国这样的北方国家迁往赤道，
the UK Europe that would be a recipe for
欧洲这将成为
for war and conflict without any doubt
战争和冲突的根源，毫无
the civilization that makes our lives so
疑问， 让我们的生活如此
comfortable also makes us vulnerable
舒适 也让我们变得脆弱
but thirteen thousand years ago that's
但一万三千年前，
less than a second to midnight on our
距离我们
clock our Stone Age ancestors were
时钟的
made it through a super eruption and an
午夜还不到一秒
ice age the risk of lightning striking a
冰河时代 第三次闪电袭击的风险
third time seems remote
似乎很遥远
sadly it wasn't the planet had done its
可悲的是这颗行星并没有达到
worst but there was still space to be
最坏的程度，但仍有不可
reckoned with
忽视的空间 在远古的
asteroids have struck earth throughout
历史中，小行星曾撞击地球，
history in the ancient past they even
它们甚至
caused mass extinctions and scientists
造成了大规模灭绝和科学家
are now beginning to wonder if humans
现在开始怀疑人类
could also have been affected by a
是否也可能受到
cosmic catastrophe this is Ohio in the
宇宙灾难的影响这是美国的俄亥俄州
USA this is the site of a major
这我 一个重大
catastrophe something happened which had
灾难的发生地发生
a profound effect on the life of the
了一些对时代生活产生深远
these days most of Ohio is farmland but
影响的事情 是农田，但
one small area of marsh remains it's
仍有一小块沼泽地
just as it was thirteen thousand years
和一万三千
ago
年前一样，
except for these
除了
back then the area was home to an
这些 那时该地区是
impressive collection of beasts
令人印象深刻的野兽集合地
there were mega mammals roaming this
有大型哺乳动物在该
area which included mammoths and
地区漫游，其中包括猛犸象和
mastodons these mega mammals were food
乳齿象 这些大型哺乳动物是食物
for the continents top predators humans
对于大陆上的顶级掠食者 人类
the people who lived here we refer to as
我们将住在这里的人称为
Clovis they were Stone Age hunter
克洛维斯 他们是石器时代的狩猎
gatherers they were hunting wild game
采集者 他们正在狩猎野生动物
and gathering wild plant foods and
和采集野生植物食物并
living in extended families these people
生活在大家庭中 这些人
had successfully adapted to the
已经成功地适应了
landscape for thousands of years and
数千年的景观，
then came a catastrophe the mega mammals
然后发生了一场灾难大型哺乳动物
went extinct their livelihood was gone
灭绝了他们的生计
forever
永远消失了
clues to the cause of this catastrophe
线索 这场灾难的原因是
my 10 meters below ground this is
我在地下 10 米处 这是
Sheridan cave it's a natural time
谢里登洞穴 这是一个天然的时间
capsule its secrets might solve the
胶囊 它的秘密可能会解开
mystery of the missing mega mammals
失踪的巨型哺乳动物
tankers Lee's work in the cave has
油轮李在洞穴中的工作
unearthed a treasure trove of
发掘了
archaeological remains all of them
考古遗迹的宝库 所有这些遗迹都可以
dating to the time of the disaster it's
追溯到那个时代 在这场灾难中，我们
a long descent down to the bottom of the
需要长时间下降到
cave and a journey back in time recent
洞穴底部，回到过去的旅程最近的
excavation has revealed a dull red layer
挖掘揭示了一个暗红色层
which marks the exact moment that the
，这标志着
mega mammals vanished from the fossil
大型哺乳动物从化石
record it's known as the Clovis layer
记录中消失的确切时刻，它被称为克洛维斯层，
we're looking at the Clovis layer it's a
我们“ 再看克洛维斯层 这是一个
very distinct layer here in the cave
非常独特的层
beneath it we have mega mammal remains
在它下面的洞穴中 我们有大型哺乳动物遗骸
above the layer there are no more mega
在该层之上 没有更多的大型
mammals this literally represents the
哺乳动物 这确实代表了
extinction event and you can find the
灭绝事件 你可以
same thing at more than twenty other
在其他二十多个地点找到同样的东西
sites across America
在整个
the sediment layer marks the exact
美国，沉积层标志着
moment the mega mammals disappeared one
大型哺乳动物消失的确切时刻
of the things that intrigues me about
，这是让我对
this time period and about this site is
这个时期和这个年代感兴趣的事情之一
we have no clear-cut answer as to what
对于
caused the extinction of these mega
导致这些大型哺乳动物灭绝的原因，我们没有明确的答案
mammals overhunting people killing these
过度捕杀这些
animals just does not fit and when we
动物的人是不合适的，当我们
look at all the other ice ages which
看到所有其他冰河时代
came to an end these mega mammals did
结束时，这些大型哺乳动物并
not go extinct so why now and why here
没有灭绝 那么为什么现在以及为什么
this is one of the most intriguing
这里是我曾经面临的最有趣的
questions that I've ever faced
问题之一 在
excavation here continues even after a
这里挖掘工作在十年后仍在继续
decade they're still digging up bones
他们仍在挖掘骨头
even though this bone looks fresh is
即使这块骨头看起来很新鲜
actually thirteen thousand years old it
实际上已经有一万三千岁了 它
dates to the extinction event and it
可以追溯到 灭绝事件，它
suggests a violent death what's really
暗示了暴力死亡
exciting about this particular specimen
这个特定标本真正令人兴奋的
is there's clear evidence of burning
是有明显的证据表明燃烧
clearly a blackened color
明显变黑
this is the tibia of a now extinct
这是现已灭绝的
pig-like creature the size of a
猪状生物的胫骨
modern-day wild boar in order to burn
现代野猪的大小为了燃烧
European wild boar we're talking about
欧洲野猪大小的动物的肉 我们谈论的
temperatures between 300 and 600 degrees
温度在 300 到 600
centigrade this is not an animal that
摄氏度之间 这
was subjected to a cooking fire this
不是遭受烹饪火的动物
animal was incinerated and so was the
动物被焚毁，
entire landscape
整个景观
we're talking about a massive fire
也被焚毁 我们正在谈论一场大火
almost an explosion of heat and pressure
几乎是热量和压力的爆炸
the question is why it's nearly midnight
问题是为什么
on our clock of the Earth's history
我们的地球历史时钟接近午夜
13,000 years ago a disaster struck
13,000 年前一场灾难袭击了
America the mega mammals were wiped out
美国 大型哺乳动物被抹去
and the people who hunted them lost
猎杀他们的人失去了
their main food source the cause of this
他们的主要食物来源这场灾难的原因
disaster has long been a mystery but
长期以来一直是个谜，但
deep in these Ohio caves archaeologist
在俄亥俄州这些洞穴深处，考古学家
Ken Tankersley has discovered something
肯·坦克斯利发现了
which might provide the answer this is a
一些可能提供答案的东西，这是一个
meter which measures the magnetism the
测量磁力的仪表
amount of iron the higher the iron
铁 铁
content the greater the magnetic
含量越高
susceptibility of this layer of first
，该层的磁化率越大 首先
put the probe in this gray area below
将探头放在 clovis 层下方的灰色区域
the clovis layer is a perfect spot and
是一个完美的点，
we check the magnetism we see that it
我们检查了磁性，我们看到
has a magnetism of eight now what we're
它的磁性为 8，现在我们是
going to do is compare that with the
要做的是与上面的层进行比较，
layer above it the reading is 50 times
读数是
the iron content in other words the
铁含量的 50 倍，换句话说，
magnetic susceptibility is 50 times
磁化率要高 50
higher than the area that's gray
倍 与灰色区域相比，
a basic experiment reveals just how rich
基本实验揭示了铁的含量有多丰富
in iron the clovis layer really is a
clovis 层实际上是一块
magnet dragged across the surface is
磁铁，被拖过表面
left covered with iron particles it's a
留下铁颗粒覆盖 这是一个
simple test with an astonishing
简单的测试，具有惊人的
implication it suggests this region was
含义 它表明该区域
hit by an asteroid this suggests that
被小行星撞击 这表明
there was some type of catastrophic
发生了某种类型的灾难性
explosion one which not only deposited
爆炸，不仅沉积了
meteoric iron but one that was also
陨铁，而且
intense in temperature and pressure an
温度和压力也很高
asteroid strike meant North America's
小行星撞击意味着北美的
mega mammals were doomed
大型哺乳动物注定要失败
they couldn't adapt to the challenging
他们无法适应灾难后的挑战性
conditions that followed the disaster
条件，
but humans could and the survivors
但人类 可以和幸存者
flourished
蓬勃发展
it's a controversial theory
这是一个有争议的理论，
but it wouldn't be the first time that
但这不是第一次
death had come from space scientists
死亡来自太空科学家
believe that 65 million years ago an
认为 6500 万年前
asteroid wiped out the dinosaurs leaving
一颗小行星消灭了恐龙
behind a giant crater
留下了一个巨大的陨石坑
crater exists but one man has a theory
陨石坑存在，但一个人有一个
which might explain why there isn't one
理论可以解释为什么没有一个
planetary geologist Peter Schultz has
行星地质学家皮特 r 舒尔茨
come to this NASA Research Center in
来到加州的这个 NASA 研究中心，
California to conduct an experiment with
用
this giant gun
这把巨大的枪进行实验，
it's so powerful it can fire projectiles
它非常强大，可以
at over 15 times the speed of sound this
以超过 15 倍的音速发射炮弹 这
is one of the big guns the fastest gun
是大枪之一 西方最快的枪
in the West this is where we have a
我们有
chance to actually fire small bullets
机会真正
small bb's at very high speed Schultz
以非常高的速度发射小子弹 舒尔茨
and his team will be firing the gun to
和他的团队将开枪以
find out if an object from space could
找出来自太空的物体是否可以
strike the earth without leaving a
在不留下陨石坑的情况下撞击地球
crater Schultz is testing a theory that
舒尔茨正在测试
glaciers could have protected the
冰川可以保护的理论
Earth's surface during the Clovis era
克洛维斯时代的地球表面
much of North America was covered by a
北美洲的大部分地区被
vast ice sheet up to a mile thick a
厚达一英里的巨大冰盖覆盖
remnant of the last big freeze shoots
最后一次大冻芽的残余
hopes a scale experiment will show where
希望规模实验能够显示
the glaciers could have prevented an
冰川可以阻止
asteroid from leaving a crater in the
小行星在何处留下陨石坑
underlying rock the question we really
底层岩石 我们真正
want to address is will the ice actually
想解决的问题是冰是否真的能
protect the earth below this is our
保护下面的地球 这是我们的
projectile it's just an eighth of an
弹丸 它只有八分之一
inch about three millimeters or so and
英寸 大约三毫米 大约 s 左右，
we're going to be firing this at a speed
我们将以
of about five kilometers per second the
大约每秒 5 公里的速度开火
team prepares the gun for firing a
团队准备枪射击
number of ultra high speed cameras will
一些超高速摄像机将
film the impact for later analysis
拍摄撞击以供稍后
inside the impact chamber Schultz
在撞击室内进行分析 舒尔茨
prepares the target the red sand
准备目标 红色的沙子
represents the surface of the earth
代表地球的表面
let's add some color at least to the
让我们至少在表面层添加一些颜色
surface layer and this way we can tell
，这样我们就可以知道
whether or not we punch it through the
我们是否将它打穿了
surface or not so we have loose sand
表面，所以我们下面有松散的沙子
underneath and we have the red layer on
，而顶部有红色层
top we're going to do one experiment
我们将做一个实验，
when we slam just into this target like
当我们像我们一样猛击这个目标
we have it and the other one where we
时，另一个实验是我们
put a thin layer of ice and the idea
放了一层薄冰，
behind that is whether or not this ice
背后的想法是这种冰
will act as a flak jacket now we just
是否可以作为防弹衣，现在我们
have one go ahead let's see what happens
让我们继续吧，让我们看看会发生
the gun is raised into the firing
什么，枪升到射击
position
位置
and the countdown begins
，倒计时
the team waits in a sealed bunker well
开始，团队在远离枪本身的密封掩体中等待
away from the gun itself Wow now that
哇，现在这
that did some damage so this is big so
造成了一些伤害，所以这是很大的，所以
forget it we're going to slow this up
我们忘记它了。 再去 放慢速度
now take a look at the slow-mo Kapow so
现在看看慢动作 Kapow 所以
this is now the entire impact with the
现在这是整个冲击与
streak through and the impact stuff
连续穿过和冲击
that's going downrange of extremely high
的东西在极
speed that clears away and we have the
高速的范围内消失，我们有
crater forming and now the critter just
陨石坑形成，现在小动物只是
grows and grows and grows and grows and
不断增长，不断增长，
keeps growing high-speed footage shows
不断增长，高速镜头显示
the devastating impact on the exposed
了对裸露沙子表面的破坏性影响，
sand surface but the best evidence is
但最好的证据是
inside the impact chamber itself now now
现在撞击室内本身
that did some damage so this this impact
造成了一些损坏，因此这种撞击
was it was a good sized impact this was
是一个很好的撞击 这是
hydro velocity has slammed in it
水流速度猛烈撞击它
excavated stuff from below we scaled
从下面挖掘出的东西我们将
this up to a big crater on the earth it
其放大到地球上的一个大火山口
would last for millions of years
它将持续数百万年
so the next day just to repair this
所以第二天只是为了修复这个
target make it look like it was before
目标让它看起来像在
we had the impact but this time let's
我们受到影响之前 但是这一次让我们
put down a slab of ice kind of
放下一块冰块 有点
resembling what might have been on the
像
earth when there were glaciers
有冰川时地球上
now we have the ice on top of the target
的冰块 现在我们在目标顶部有冰块
and what we want to know is whether or
我们想知道
not this ice actually buffers or
这是否 冰实际上缓冲或
protects the underlying target from the
保护潜在目标免受
impact
影响
she's sweet and we see that the vapor
她是甜蜜的，我们看到蒸汽
expands and we're seeing a little bit of
膨胀，我们看到一点点
ice come out
冰出来
and the ice clears away and the real
，冰消失了，真正的
question and for the anxious to see if
问题是急于看看
is without we really produce it created
是否没有 我们真的生产它
right now I don't see a crater oh man
现在我没有看到一个火山口哦
that's remarkable the ice was here and
，了不起的人，这里的冰
it really protected the target
真的保护了
underneath and that's just simply loose
下面的目标，只是松散的
and so with time these pieces disappear
，所以随着时间的推移，这些碎片消失了，
they melt away and only has it has a
它们融化了，只有它有一个
tunneling crater and if this were the
挖隧道的陨石坑，如果这是
earth that could be really easily eroded
地球真的很容易被侵蚀
away and so when that ice disappears
掉，那么当冰消失时，
there's just nothing left it's the
什么也没有留下，这是
perfect crime
完美的犯罪，
it's only a scale model but it shows a
它只是一个比例模型，但它表明一张
nice sheet could have masked the
漂亮的床单可能掩盖
evidence of a powerful impact 13,000
了强大影响的证据 13,000
years ago maybe the mega mammals were
几年前，也许
wiped out by a cosmic catastrophe one
有一天大型哺乳动物被一场宇宙灾难消灭了，
day we may face a similar disaster
我们可能会面临类似的灾难
advanced warning will be essential for
提前警告对
our survival
我们的生存至关重要，
something astronomers in Arizona are
这是亚利桑那州的天文学家 na
working to provide this is Mount Lemmon
正在努力提供这
station part of the Steward Observatory
是 Steward 天文台的莱蒙山站的一部分，
here asteroid hunter ed be sure comb
这里是小行星猎人 ed 确保
space for near-earth objects any OHS
为近地天体梳理空间 任何 OHS
there are millions out there right now
现在那里有数以百万计的人
and not surprisingly governments
，毫不奇怪，
worldwide consider them a real threat
全世界的政府都认为它们是地球的真正
well the earth traveling around the Sun
威胁 绕太阳
is much like a race car
行驶很像赛车
traveling around a circular track and a
在环形轨道上行驶，而
neo collision might be very much like a
neo碰撞可能非常像一辆
car coming suddenly out of the pits in
汽车突然从赛车前面的坑里出来，
front of the race cars representing an
代表着
immediate impact threat and of course
直接的撞击威胁，当然还有碰撞
the consequences of a collision would be
的后果 每天晚上碰撞都会是
devastating
毁灭性的，
each night be Shaw's team photographed
因为 Shaw 的团队
the skies searching for anything that
拍摄天空寻找任何
moves
移动的东西
hey Andrea have a look at this it's
嘿 Andrea 看看这个它
really fast yeah it's quite bright its
真的很快是的它非常明亮，它的
19th magnitude and it's got a digest
19 等并且它的摘要
score of a hundred let's check if it is
分数是 100 让我们检查它是否
norm yeah
正常是的
there's no ID on this this object is
这个物体上没有 ID
the team have found an nao it's
团队发现了一个 nao 这是
painstaking but vital work we take four
艰苦但至关重要的工作我们
images over it space over about 45
在它上面拍了四张图片空间在 ab 上 45
minutes about 10 minutes apart so here
分钟 大约相隔 10 分钟 所以在这里
you see four images being shown in
你会看到四张图像依次显示
our computers register the images so
我们的计算机记录了这些图像，
that the stars don't move but any object
这样星星就不会移动，但是任何
which is moving on the sky is revealed
在天空中移动的物体都会显示出来，
like you see the object here fortunately
就像你在这里看到的物体一样，幸运的是，
this near-earth object is probably
离我们很近 -地球物体可能是
harmless this object is in fact what's
无害的 这个物体实际上是
called a virtual impactor which means
所谓的虚拟撞击器，这
that there is a small very small
意味着未来可能发生撞击的可能性很小很小
probability that there might be an
，
impact in the future it's big but
但
luckily it poses little risk but for
幸运的是它带来的风险很小，但对于
every large object in space there are
太空中的每个大型物体 有
many thousands of smaller ones and they
成千上万个较小的物体，它们
can pose a real threat
可以构成真正的
the asteroids are like gravel if you
威胁 小行星就像砾石 如果你
pick up a handful of gravel you're going
拿起一把砾石 你
to find that there's a few large objects
会发现里面有一些大
in there but there's a whole lot more
物体 但还有很多更
smaller objects and it may be these
小的物体 可能是这些
smaller objects that in fact might be on
较小的物体实际上可能
a collision course with the earth
与地球发生碰撞
and you don't have to look far to see
，您不必走远就能
what even a small asteroid can do this
看到即使是小行星也能做到的事情 这
is meteor crater in Arizona 50000 years
是亚利桑那州的陨石坑 50000
ago this impact devastated hundreds of
年前，这次撞击摧毁了数百
square miles and the asteroid that did
平方英里，造成撞击的小行星
it
只有 50 米宽，但如果您
think 50 metres is small check this out
认为 50 米很小，请查看
this is the aftermath of a large
这是 1908 年西伯利亚
explosion in the remote Tunguska region
偏远通古斯地区发生大爆炸的后果。
of Siberia in 1908 fallen trees fanned
树木
out from a central blast point for
从中央爆炸点散开
hundreds of miles
数百英里
there could be only one cause an
可能只有一个原因导致
asteroid exploding with the power of a
小行星以
nuclear bomb and it's estimated size
核弹的威力爆炸，它的大小估计
just 10 meters across
只有 10 米穿过
Tunguska is the only hard evidence we
通古斯是
have of a recent impact on planet Earth
我们最近对地球产生影响的唯一确凿证据 地球，
so we can look about and say that's
所以我们可以环顾四周，说
pretty scary if that was a city
如果
underneath there it would be completely
在那里有一座城市，它会被完全
obliterated and it's quite interesting
摧毁，这是非常可怕的，而且很有趣的
that if you look at the area that was
是，如果你看看被摧毁的区域
destroyed and superimpose it on London
并将其叠加在伦敦
for example virtually the entire area of
上，例如几乎整个
Greater London would be wiped out
大区域 伦敦将被消灭
this catastrophe shows just how
这场灾难表明
vulnerable we are
我们是多么脆弱
Tunguska sized projectiles strike earth
通古斯大小的射弹
roughly once a century the last one was
大约一个世纪一次撞击地球最后一次是
a hundred years ago another deadly
一百年前，另一颗致命的
asteroid could turn up any day
小行星随时可能
the history of our planet is an endless
出现 我们星球的历史是一个永无止境
cycle of extinction and rebirth so it
的灭绝和重生循环 因此
should come as no surprise that we
，我们
humans are as vulnerable as our
人类与
predecessors who are long extinct we've
早已灭绝的祖先一样脆弱也就不足为奇了 我们
suffered disasters but not on a global
遭受了灾难 但不是在全球
scale if we had we wouldn't be here at
范围内，如果我们有的话，我们根本不会在这里
it's not that we've been lucky it's just
这不是我们很幸运，
that we haven't been unlucky yet
只是我们还没有倒霉